Enrique Hermo

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Address: Dublin, Ireland

E-mail: enrique.hermo@gmail.com

Citizenship: Spanish

Profile

Solutions Architect and Technical Lead with 4 years' experience guiding teams across all software development phases. Strong contributor to project management, 10 years' hands-on technical expertise and functional analysis skills to define business objectives and project scope, 6 of them in telecom industry. Highly personable and self-motivated professional with the versatility to work in complex scenarios. Excellent communicator with emphasis on describing complex or technical issues in layman's terms. Quick learner that rapidly adapts to emerging technologies.

Latest Projects

2014 Production support for satellite TV provider SKY, Mexico Customer post-go-live support for OSS/BSS solution. The number of subscribers is 4 millions and increasing. The solution is handling up to one hundred eighty thousand daily transactions.

2012 Order Manager solution for satellite TV provider SKY, Mexico Design and implementation of an OSS/BSS solution in order to manage several types of pre-paid and post-paid uses cases.

2012 Order Service Management Troubleshooting TDC, Denmark Diagnosis to identify bottlenecks and stabilize OSS solution in production environment.

2011 OSS/BSS solution for SIM order fulfillment Vodafone UK, England Implementation of a OSS/BSS solution with service order management for Machine to Machine (M2M) SIM order fulfillment.

2010 Telecommunication business integration platform Vodafone, Spain Design and construction of a business integration platform between Vodafone and the incumbent operator Telefonica to consume deregulated services (OSB, J2EE, WebServices, Oracle BAM).

Professional Experience

Solutions Architect

September 2012 – December 2014

Mobile: (+353) 892476032

LinkedIn: enrique-hermo

Personal Website: webCV

Optare Solutions S.L., Vigo, Spain

- Creation of documentation, proposals, presentation material
- Discovery sessions with the customer
- Gathering requirements and high level solution design
- Project estimation and resource planning to execute the project
- Communication of technical details, best practices and limitations
- Lead the development, testing and maintenance activities
- Training customer team

Telecom Consultant

October 2011 - September 2012

Optare Solutions S.L., Vigo, Spain

- Configure, tune, and test for functionality, performance and capacity
- Hands-on experience in development

- Experience with high availability and clustering in WebLogic servers
- Experience with WebLogic messaging services and integration

Junior Solutions Architect

February 2011 - October 2011

Optare Solutions S.L., Vigo, Spain

- Requirements analysis and definition system overview
- Determine and document the vision for the target product or system
- Initial estimation listing what is included in the price, as well as why and how much any additional features will cost
- Rough project schedule and resource planning

Analyst/Developer

March 2009 – February 2011

Optare Solutions S.L., Vigo, Spain

- Lead the development
- Hands-on experience with high availability and clustering in WebLogic Servers
- Hands-on experience with Oracle Service Bus, Oracle BAM and Oracle Metasolv

Analyst/Developer

October 2006 – February 2009

Ventura24, Madrid, Spain

- Develop and maintain a JEE eCommerce platform: creating technical concepts, task evaluation, implementation, documentation and unit testing
- 24/7 technical support L2 where shifts rotate
- Experience with Struts and PL/SQL
- Experience with Eclipse, Maven and Subversion

Analyst/Developer

April 2005 - October 2006

Telenium, Madrid, Spain

- Develop and maintain a JEE Healthcare System
- Hands-on experience with Oracle databases, JavaScript, JSP and Servlets
- Technical support during release at customer's premises
- Responsive support L2 to clients during normal business hours

Developer

October 2004 – April 2005

Deutsche Post IT Solutions, Darmstadt, Germany

EDUCATION

University of Vigo, Vigo, Spain

1998 - 2004

MS in Telecommunications engineering (Information Technology)

Courses

■ Machine Learning

Coursera, 2014

Agile IT Project Management and Direction with SCRUM, SCRUMBAN and LEAN software Optare Solutions, 2014 ■ PMI Project Management training

University of Vigo, 2013

■ TM Forum Information Framework (SID) Distilled

TM Forum, 2012

■ TM Forum Information Framework (SID) Modeler 's Workshop TM Forum, 2012

■ Enterprise integration patterns & JAVA

Optare Solutions, 2011

■ Complementary course of English phonetics

EOI Vigo, 2011

■ Basic level in Chinese language

EOI Vigo, 2011

 OPN Oracle SOA Suite 11g: Implementation Boot Camp. SOA Suite, Oracle Service Bus, BAM
Oracle University, 2010

■ Spring and Hibernate

Oose Innovative Informatik, 2008

CERTIFICATIONS

■ Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems

Coursera, 2014

■ Certified ScrumMaster®

Scrum Alliance®, 2014

■ Oracle Comms Order and Service Management PreSales Specialist Oracle, 2014

■ Oracle Comms Order and Service Management Sales Specialist Oracle, 2014

■ IELTS, General Training, 7.5 Cambridge English Language Assessment, 2014

Oracle Comms Order and Service Management Server 7
Certified Implementation Specialist

Oracle University, 2014

■ Games without Chance: Combinatorial Game Theory

Coursera, 2014

■ Information Framework (SID) Level 2

TMForum, 2012

■ First certificate in English Cambridge English Language Assessment, 1997

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Oracle: Oracle Databases, Oracle Service Bus, Oracle Comms Order and Service Management 7, Oracle BAM, Oracle Comms Metasolv Solution 6.0
- TM Forum: eTOM, SID standards
- WebLogic Servers: Administration, high availability, clusterization, SAF configuration
- Others servers: : Apache, Weblogic Server, Jboss, Jetty, Orion, Oracle AS
- Programming: J2EE, Java, Groovy, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML, XML, XPath, XQuery, Bash scripting, WLST, JavaScript, JSP, Servlets, Struts
- Tools: SVN, CVS, JIRA, Mantis, Track, Bugzilla, Quartz Scheduler, Maven, Ant, SOAPUI, LOADUI, HermesJMS, Toad, PLSQL Developer, Eclipse, WLI Workshop, Visual Paradigm, MS Visio, MS Project
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

LANGUAGES

Spanish Native language

English Advanced, both written and spoken

2014 IELTS General Training 7.5

German Intermediate, both written and spoken

Level B2 MCER